University of Connecticut, Regional Campus Records 1999.0089
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, Regional Campus Records
1950-2011
1999.0089
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
12.95 Linear feet
Records from the Greater Hartford and Stamford Regional Campuses of the University of Connecticut.
History
The Greater Hartford campus at the University of Connecticut was founded on October 2, 1939, in Hartford, Connecticut, was officially recognized as the Hartford branch of the University in 1946, and moved to its present location in West Hartford in 1970. The campus provides students in the capital area the flexibility to work and also attend classes and enjoy the opportunities offered by the university in a more accessible location. The campus offers a wide variety of liberal arts and science courses, and caters to over 1400 undergraduate and 600 graduate students. Also located at the Greater Hartford campus is the university's School of Social Work.
The Stamford campus at the University of Connecticut was founded in 1951 to provide veterans returning from the Korean War with a more convenient educational facility. The campus offers degrees in ten major areas of study, including History, American Studies, English, and Political Science. In addition to undergraduate programs, the Stamford Campus offers a Master's of Business Administration and an Executive Master's of Business Administration degree. The campus is located in southeastern Connecticut, and provides students in Fairfield County and the surrounding area with access to the university's excellent resources.
Scope and Content Note
The Regional Campus records are comprised of two series. The first series consists of records from the Stamford Campus from the years 1950 to 2006. The second series consists of publications from the Greater Hartford Campus from the years 1988 to 2011.
The records from the Greater Hartford branch include schedules of classes and course syllabi.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Provenance and Acquisition
The records are transferred to the University Archives by the campuses periodically.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students, etc. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
University of Connecticut; University of Connecticut; Administrative records.; Archives (institutions).; Publications.; University of Connecticut.
- Series I: Stamford Campus Records, 1950-2006
  - Illustrations, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Manuscripts, Fliers, Publications, Administrative and Financial Records, 1962-2006 (Box S_1)
    Scope and Contents note
    [Subjects include: Connecticut Daily Campus, History of Sports.]
  - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, 1995-1996 (Box S_2)
    [Subjects include: UConn Academics.]
  - Administrative Records, Manuscripts, Publications, 1955-1977 (Box S_3)
    [Subjects include: "4 Year College at Stamford", Reports.]
  - Administrative Records, Manuscripts, Newspaper Clippings, Scrapbook, 1954-1955 (Box S_4)
    [Subjects include: Stamford Center Undergraduate Program, UConn Funds.]
  - Newspaper Clippings, Publications, Manuscripts, Administrative and Financial Records, Notes, 1950-1999 (Box S_5)
    [Subjects include: Histories of UConn Stamford, Publications.]
  - Administrative and Financial Records, Transparency, Newspaper Clippings, Correspondence, Publications, 1959-1960 (Box S_6)
    [Subjects include: Bylaws, meeting minutes on buildings, News and Radio Releases.]
  - Administrative Records, Notes, 1959 (Box S_7)
  - Administrative and Financial Records, Correspondence, Manuscripts, Newspaper Clippings, Notes, Publications, 1959-1960 (Box S_8)
    [Subjects include: UConn Branch Building Funds, Campaign Office, Committees.]
- Series II: Greater Hartford Campus Records, 1988-2011
  - Publications, 1988-2010 (Box GH_1)
    [Subjects include: Schedules of classes, syllabi.]
  - Publications, 2010-2011 (Box GH_2)
    [Subjects include: course syllabi.]
  - Administrative records, minutes, correspondence, publications, undated, 1999-2004 (Box GH_3)
    Scope and Content Note
    [Subjects include: Hartford Consortium, 5th graders go to college, 1999-2003; Tri-Campus activities (administrative records), 2002-2003; Admissions publications, circa 2001; Hartford Public Schools, Foundation for Public Schools, 2004 .]
  - Administrative records, clippings, correspondence, 1986-1997 (Box GH_4)
  - Syllabi, undated, 2009-2010 (Box GH_4)
  - Clippings and Correspondence (about faculty), 1986-2009 (Box GH_4)
  - Constitution Plaza project (campus move/consolidation), 1995-1998 (Box GH_4)
- Series III: Waterbury Campus Records, undated, 2002
  - Administrative records (Box GH_3)
    [Subjects include: Center for Academic Programs, 2002; "Top Choice," undated; Proposal, 2002.]
- Series IV: Torrington Campus Records, undated
  - Publication, undated (Box GH_3)
    [Subjects include: "Top Choice," undated.]
- Series V: Tri-Campus Records, 2006
  The Tri-Campus location existed from to and included the Waterbury, Torrington and Greater Hartford Campuses.
  - University of Connecticut 2006, 1999-0089/DVD1; 1 DVD (7:33 min.): sd., col. (Disk 1999-0089/DVD1)
    Developed for Tri-Campus with special focus on the Greater Hartford Campus.